我叫巴里·艾伦
My name is Barry Allen,
是现今世上速度最快的人
and I am the fastest man alive.
在外人看来
To the outside world,
我只是个普通的鉴证专员
I'm an ordinary forensic scientist.
但在尖端科研实验室
But secretly, with the help
朋友们的帮助下
of my friends at S.T.A.R. Labs,
我秘密地打击犯罪  寻找跟我一样的超能力者
I fight crime and find other meta-humans like me.
但当我女儿从未来时空前来帮忙
But when my daughter came back from the future to help,
她改变了现在
she changed the present
现在我们的世界比以往更加危险
and now our world is more dangerous than ever
我是唯一一个来得及拯救世界的人
and I'm the only one fast enough to save it.
我是闪电侠
I am the Flash.
《闪电侠》前情回顾
Previously on "The Flash"...
救救她
Save her.
我们的生活比过去好了很多
Our life is a million times better than what it was
这都是因为你  格蕾丝
and it's all because of you, Gracie.
给你带了些生活用品
Got you some groceries
还有美洛昔康用于你的伤口
and some meloxicam for your injuries.
我们叫它解药
We call it the cure.
是一种血清  能抑制超能力者体内的暗物质
It's a serum that suppresses dark matter in meta-humans.
你是第一个接受的人
You're the first person to take it.
我们应该给蝉一份解药
I think we should offer the cure to Cicada.
诺拉·韦斯特·艾伦日记
From the journal of Nora West-Allen:
翻译结果
时间线是有延展性的
Timeline is malleable.
她为什么要隐瞒自己对此感兴趣呢
Why is she hiding this interest?
告诉我你知道你在做什么
Tell me you know what you're doing.
我是唯一知道自己在做什么的极速者
I am the only speedster who knows what he's doing!
按照计划进行
Stick with the plan.
解药合成了  而且有效
The cure is finished, and it works.
我们可以给德怀尔用了
Now we can use it on Dwyer,
他和匕首的联系就会断开
and then his connection to the dagger will be broken.
有什么问题吗
What's wrong?
时间线
The timeline.
从第一个男孩安瑟罗到最后一个男孩卡曼迪
I've charted this timeline from Anthro the First Boy
我一直在跟踪记录时间线
to Kamandi the Last.
我一切都知道
I know all of it.
我知道它的高峰和低谷
I know its crests, I know its valleys,
我知道怎么做才能打败蝉
I know what we must do to defeat Cicada.
或者说  我曾经知道
Or rather, I knew.
闪电侠与蝉交战
超能力者杀手仍逍遥法外
这是闪电侠和蝉最后一次
This is a photo of the last public sighting
中城图片新闻
出现在公众视野
of Flash and Cicada.
这是他们最后的对峙
Their final confrontation.
爸爸给蝉用解药的最后机会
Dad's last chance to use the cure on Cicada.
自从我到了那里
I've been trying to engineer a moment like this
就一直努力创造这种机会
the whole time I've been there.
你看
Now, watch.
看见了吗
See this?
这个新的时间线挣扎着想要冲破障碍
That is a new timeline struggling to break through,
将自己展现在我们眼前
manifesting itself right before our eyes.
这时间线是好是坏
Is it a good timeline, or is it a bad timeline?
不重要
That doesn't matter.
重要的是  它是新的  也就无法预知
What matters is it's new and, as such, unpredictable,
并且我们可能失去宝贵的机会
and we may lose our window of opportunity.
所以我们要在时间线改变之前找到蝉
So we need to find Cicada before the timeline changes.
为什么会改变
Why did it change?
是我哪里搞砸了吗
Did I screw something up?
不是
No.
并不是
No, no.
你做得很好  小极速者
You've done very well, little runner.
但新的变量即将到来  重要的事即将到来
But a new variable is coming, something big is coming.
或者是某人
Or someone.
闪 电 侠
第五季
第十六集
先生  你这么说有点意思
Well, it's interesting that you say that, sir,
因为是你的公司拒绝了
since it's your company that's denying
罗伯森一家的索赔
the Robertson family's claim.
当然  合同就在我眼前
Yes, of course, I have the contract right in front of me.
上面写着动物袭击
And it says that animal attacks
不属于自然灾害
do not fall under Acts of God,
而大猩猩是动物的一种
and that includes gorillas.
《公民报》期待您给出的说法
The Citizen looks forward to your statement.
多谢  亲爱的
Thanks, babe.
你准备好这么做了吗
Are you ready to do this thing now?
没错  就差把诺拉找来了
Hell yeah, we just got to find Nora.
这毕竟是她的大日子
It's her big day after all.
希望她不是特别忙  你说呢
You don't think she's too busy, do you?
好  各位想一想
Okay, people, think!
自从屋顶对战后我们就没见过蝉了
We haven't seen Cicada since the rooftop fight,
也就是说  想要找到他的唯一办法就是
which means the only way to track him down is to figure out
可能的超能力者?
找出哪个超能力者是他的下一个目标
who his next meta-human target's gonna be.
蝉是谁?
每个银行抢劫和非法闯入实验室的案件
Have we double checked every bank robbery,
都再查过一遍了吗
every lab break-in?
查了  我们都查过了  好吧
Yes, yes! We have looked at all of that, all right?
所有被监禁的罪犯
And all the criminals that are in custody
都是普通人
are simply mere mortals.
那街上的那些人呢
What about the ones on the street?
冰霜杀手说诺瓦克被列入联邦证人保护计划后
Frost says that no new metas have shown up
就没有新的超能力者出现了
since Norvock went into WITSEC.
卫星在监测暗物质或者
Are the satellites tracking for dark matter
超能力者基因爆发或者X元素吗
or meta-gene bursts or Element X?
是是是
Yes, yes, and yes.
一切都在它们的监测之下
They're scanning for everything.
恭喜  你的威慑力上了一个档次
Congratulations, you raised a menace.
你女儿  真是年轻气盛
Your daughter, so energetic.
你刚刚那一通  还真厉害
This is pretty impressive.
我知道  现在解药有效了
Um, and I... and I know with the cure working,
我们也都做好打败蝉的准备了
we're all ready to put Cicada to rest,
不过他一定很快就会出现的
but I'm sure he'll resurface soon.
所以你打算给他机会
And then you're going to give him the chance
使用超能力者解药
to take the meta-human cure?
没错
Yes, exactly.
德怀尔也应该有选择的权利
Even Dwyer deserves a choice,
我们只需要说服他做正确的事情
we just got to convince him to do the right thing.
你准备好了吗
Are you ready?
这将会是你英雄生涯
This is gonna be one of the biggest challenges
最大的挑战之一
of your career as a hero.
你知道自己要说什么吗
Do you know what you're going to say?
这个...  应该吧
Oh, yeah... you know, yeah.
我...  我有些零星的想法
I've... I've got some loose thoughts.
好极了
Oh, great.
这话给了我们所有人信心对吧
Well, that instills all of us with confidence, right?
零星的想法  你打算怎么说
Loose thoughts? What are you going to say?
最残忍的敌人  住手
"Hey, most bloodthirsty enemy! Stop."
各位  这话对马尔利泽有用
Guys, it worked for Marlize.
也许对萨维塔就没什么用  但是
Maybe not so much for Savitar, but...
我会好好想想该和他说什么的
I will figure out what to say to him, all right?
交给我
I got this.
我知道你可以的  老爸
I know you do, Dad.
所以我们要尽全力找到他
Which is why we need to try everything to try and find him.
好吗
Okay?
也许我们应该开始巡逻
Maybe we should go on patrol?
-你说巡逻吗  -这是干吗  打二战吗
- Patrol, you say? - What this is, World War II?
简直是疯了
Wow, this is crazy.
吉特发生了大事
There is something nuts going on at Jitters.
你认为是超能力者吗
Do you think it's a meta-human?
-也许是吧  -你应该...
- Probably. - You should...
-我们应该去看看  -好
- We should check it out. - Yeah.
-当然  -好
- For sure. - Yeah.
-没错  快去  -我...
- Y-yeah. Go! - I'm...
-是你们俩搞出来的  -你们生了她
- You two did this. - You made her.
你们责无旁贷
You are responsible.
中城警局
证物
蝉目击报告  行动报告
快看看
Well, well, well.
很高兴看到某人回到办公桌前了
It is nice to see someone back at his desk.
小狐狸
Oh, hey, Foxy.
我也很高兴回来了
It's good to be back.
小酌了三个月沃利的西藏酥油茶
After three months of sipping Wally's Tibetan butter tea,
其实我还挺想念这杯休息室的咖啡的
I actually kind of missed this break room coffee.
你知不知道我上哪能拿到
Hey, you have any idea where I can get my hands
蝉的特别行动小组文件
on the Cicada task force file?
宝贝  都在你身边
Babe, you're standing in it.
什么
What?
我一直想赶上进度
I've been trying to catch up on what I've been missing.
说到这个
Uh, speaking of which...
你见过这个女人嘛
you ever seen this woman?
凡妮莎·安布勒斯医生
Uh, Dr. Vanessa Ambres.
中城医院
凡妮莎·安布勒斯医生
中城土生土长
Born and raised in Central City,
在麦克奈德大学念取医学博士学位
got her MD from McNider U.
这个有意思
Oh, that's interesting.
这上面说在大悟之道那晚
This says she treated Orlin Dwyer and Grace Gibbons
她治疗过奥林·德怀尔和格蕾丝·吉本斯
on the night of the Enlightenment.
是的  而且之后  她一直在治疗格蕾丝
Yes, and she has been treating Grace ever since,
尽管她是名急诊医生
even though she's an ER doctor,
并且护士上报说在昏迷病房里
and the nurses report a whole slew of drugs missing
有很多药物不见了
from the coma ward.
你认为她在和德怀尔联手吗
You think she's working with Dwyer?
那家伙被人捅刀子  被闪电击中
The guy got stabbed, struck by lightning.
他胸口有个洞
He's got a hole in his chest.
总得有人帮他缝针吧
Somebody has got to be patching him up, right?
我觉得我们应该去找这位医生问问
I think we should be asking the doctor a few questions.
我们去找她吧
All right, let's do it.
你要一起去吗
Oh, you want to come with?
-我要一起去  -怎么了
- Yeah, I want to come with. - What?
那好吧
Uh, yeah, yeah.
-好  -那好  搭档
- Yeah! - All right, partner.
-搭档  我喜欢  -嗯
- Partner. I like that. - Yeah.
吉特咖啡
我还以为这出大事了
Okay, I thought something big was supposed to be going on down here.
不好说  事情的确不小
Oh, I don't know. It's pretty big.
让你大饱眼福一下
Feast your eyes on the newest addition
吉特菜单的最新产品
to the Jitters menu.
XS意式特浓咖啡
The XS-presso.
有以我名字命名的饮品了
I got my own drink!
超酷炫的对吧
It's pretty schway, right?
想想接下来能弄些什么
Think of what could be next.
XS公仔  XS日
An XS action figure? XS Day?
你们说得我都不好意思了
Guys, you are embarrassing me.
我们只是真的很兴奋
We're just really excited.
我们都没有一起去旅行过
I mean, we still haven't even gone on a trip together
或是做埃丝特祖母最拿手的地瓜派
or made Grandma Esther's famous sweet potato pie recipe.
你把唱卡拉OK加进去清单里了吗
Did you put karaoke on the list like I asked?
应该加了
I think so, actually.
-等一下  -让我看看
- Just a sec... - Let me see this.
滑雪
偷偷爬上吉特屋顶
高空滑索
去塞巴斯蒂亚诺吃饭
《星球大战》电影马拉松
激光射击游戏
教诺拉开车
露营
唱卡拉OK
洛奇午夜放映
清单上列了好多事
Okay, there are so many things on this list.
我们有得是时间
Well, I mean, we've got time.
这次是真的警报  还是另一个假的
Okay, is that a real alert or another fake one?
不  这次是真的
No, this one's real.
中城大学化学系有罪案发生
M-20 at CCU, Chemistry Department.
-超能力者袭击  -没错  我们走  快
- A meta attack. - Yeah, let's go. Come on.
虽然离开高中化学课堂有段时间了
Been a while since high school chem,
但你做的肯定不符合实验安全条例
but that does not look like proper lab safety.
我需要这个  离我远点
I need this! Leave me alone!
碳酸氢钠能中和任何一种酸
Sodium bicarbonate neutralizes any acid.
你带了手铐吗
You have the cuffs?
我们去抓他
Let's go get him.
-不必  -什么
- We don't need to. - What?
看看这个灼烧的痕迹
Look at this burn mark.
中城图片新闻
闪电侠与蝉交战  超能力者杀手仍逍遥法外
那个制酸人  拍下那张照片的时候
That acid guy, he... he must've been there
他肯定也在那里
when the photo was taken.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
爸  今天就是你阻止蝉的日子
Dad, today's the day you stop Cicada.
慢一点  再说一遍
Slow down. Say that again?
在闪电侠博物馆里有一张闪电侠和蝉的照片
There's a photo, it's in The Flash museum, of Flash and Cicada...
是他们最后一次
the last time they were ever seen
在公共场合对峙
confronting each other in public,
在那张照片里  在闪电侠脚边
and in the photo, by Flash's feet,
有一个一模一样的灼伤痕迹
the exact same burn mark left by the meta
正是我们刚刚交手的超能力者留下的
that we just fought.
这个制酸超能力者出现在他们最终对战中吗
This acid meta was at their final confrontation?
他肯定是蝉的最终目标
He must be Cicada's final target.
在我消失之前  这是他的最终目标
His final target before I vanish
他又开始杀人了
and he starts killing again.
这么至关重要的超能力者
Why is Nora just telling us
诺拉为什么现在才说
about this crucial meta now?
因为我的时间线上有很多事都不靠谱
Because a lot of the stuff from my timeline is unreliable.
不同的超能力者  不同的受害者
You know, uh, different metas, different victims,
不同的情况
different circumstances.
但是这次  一切完全相同
But this time, everything's exactly the same.
目前为止是的
So far.
如果蝉去猎杀这个制酸超能力者
If Cicada goes after this acid meta,
那就意味着今天是我们
that means that today's the last day
能正面对抗他的最后一天
we're going to confront him.
也是我们能阻止他的最后机会
And our last chance to stop him.
那好吧  我得去想一想
Yeah, all right, well, then, I gotta figure out exactly
我要对他说些什么
what I'm gonna say to him.
你会想出来的  爸爸  我会帮你的
You'll find the words, Dad. I'll help you.
那我去继续捣鼓面部识别
And I am going to start working on facial rec
找这个制酸大师
for this Acid Master.
没错  这就是我要做的
Yup, that's what I'm going with.
要一直相信你的直觉  孩子们
Always trust your gut, kids.
而我们需要找出能让你和蝉对话
And we'll figure out a way for you to talk to Cicada
还不让他杀掉你的方法
without him killing you.
好吧
Well...
如果一切都顺利的话
if it all works out, then...
看来今天就是我们旅程的终点了
looks like today could be the end of our journey.
是啊
Yeah.
然后大家就要各走自己的路了
And I guess everyone starts moving on.
-诺拉  -妈妈
- Nora. - Oh, hey, Mom.
我得赶快去帮助爸爸了
Um, look, I've really gotta hurry and go help Dad.
是  我知道  只是...
Yeah, I know, it's just...
我想明天你可能就要回家了
I guess you might be going home tomorrow.
是啊  我想也是  任务完成了
Yeah, I guess so. Um, mission accomplished.
如果你俩需要休息一下的话
Well, if you two need a break after a while,
乔爷爷教了我韦斯特家族著名的右勾拳
Papa Joe taught me the famous West family right hook.
我很乐意教给你
I-I would love to teach you.
-诺拉  -抱歉  抱歉妈妈
- Nora? - Sorry, uh, sorry, Mom.
我就是想  想到了些什么
I just, uh, thought of something
可以帮助到爸爸  我得走了
that's going to help Dad... I-I got to go.
宝贝  这可是第一次
Babe, this is a first!
咱们之前不也合作过
We've worked together before.
我们是有过  警探
We have, Detective,
但是我们之前做的都跟这一次不一样
but anytime we did anything even close to this,
我之前没有能力
I didn't have my abilities.
好了  开始吧
Okay, here we go.
如果我开始捣鼓我的戒指
Uh, if I fiddle with my ring, you know,
就代表她在撒谎
assume that means she's lying
然后你就介入然后...
and then you just get in there and, mm, mm,
干你擅长的事
do your thing.
警察状态上身吧
You cop it up.
强的松  雷帕霉素  阿巴西普
Prednisone, sirolimus, abatacept.
都是被列为免疫抑制剂类的药品
All drugs classified as immunosuppressants.
它们都正巧在你工作的机构被上报失窃
They also happen to have all been reported stolen from this facility.
我知道那些报告
I'm aware of the report.
我感到好奇的是
What I'm wondering is
为什么这会引起地方检察官的注意
why it warrants the interest of the DA?
我们认为那些丢失的药物
We believe that the missing medications
与一些大案子有所关联
are connected to a much higher profile case.
奥林·德怀尔
Orlin Dwyer.
格蕾丝·吉本斯的叔叔
Grace Gibbons' uncle.
他还在逃吗  我不怎么看新闻
Is he still at large? I don't really watch the news.
是的  他还在逃中
Yes, he's very much at large.
而我们有原因相信正是这些药物
And we have reason to believe that those exact medications
能帮助德怀尔治疗他的伤势
are the ones that Dwyer would need to treat his injuries.
你究竟想表达什么
What are you saying exactly?
药物丢失的记录
The records of the stolen meds
在德怀尔停止来医院后还在继续
continued after Dwyer stopped visiting the hospital.
也就是说这里有人
Which means that someone here
或许还在给他提供药物
may be still supplying them to him.
听起来是个不错的理论
Sounds like a good theory,
但我不知道可能是谁
but I don't know who that could be.
我知道的一切都在那些报告里
Everything I know is in those reports.
好吧  好吧
Okay, okay.
现在这样就足够了
That's enough for now.
谢谢你抽出时间配合
Thank you very much for your time.
当然
Of course.
你在做什么
What are you doing?
你就这么让她走掉了
You're just gonna let her walk away like that?
我不想吓到她
I-I didn't want to scare her.
我们没有足够的证据
We don't have enough evidence.
我们连动机都没有
We don't even have a motive.
那就让我继续用我的能力
So, then, let me keep doing my thing!
我还不习惯在面谈时
I'm not used to going into an interview
加入你的能力进行考虑
factoring in your meta-abilities.
我习惯的是运用我的直觉
I-I'm used to going in using my gut.
那我的直觉呢
What about my gut?
无意冒犯  但这跟你的直觉无关
All due respect, this isn't about your gut.
你看  塞西尔  我想说的是
Look, Cecile, what I meant to say was...
不不不不  乔
No, no, no, no, no, no, Joe.
你说得对就是那意思
You said exactly what you meant,
你猜怎么着  现在
and you know what, right now,
我也要说些真心话了
I'm about to say something that I mean.
也许我们就不该一起办这个案子
Maybe we shouldn't be working on this together after all.
这下糟了
Oh, man.
好了  时间不多了
Okay, the clock's ticking,
我们还没搞清怎么劝说蝉
and we have no clue how to convince Cicada
服用解药
to take the cure,
但是我们依然有着最棒的武器
but we still have our best weapon.
-你的日记  -你的传奇
- Your journal. - Your legacy.
历史记载中关于闪电侠
One of the biggest things history remembers
最强大的一个能力
about The Flash is your ability
就是改变人们的内心和思想
to change people's hearts and minds,
尤其是你敌人的
especially your enemy's,
我这里可记载着很多这种事情呢
and I have dozens of entries about those times.
你那里有没有未来
Any chance you've got the future words
我会对蝉说的话
I say to Cicada in there?
没有  但我有你过去说过的话
Nope, but I have your past words.
磁红女  她想把油罐车砸向医院
Magenta, she wanted to drop an oil tanker on a hospital,
但你劝说她是个好人
but you convinced her she was a good person.
你说"用那份善意去打败邪恶"
You said, "Use that good to beat the bad."
磁红女有分裂人格
Magenta had split personalities.
她是真的有善恶两面
She literally had a good side and a bad side.
对蝉不会起作用的
That's not gonna work with Cicada.
莱昂纳多·史纳特
Leonard Snart,
他说他不想被拯救
he said he didn't want to be saved
但你还是想出办法说服他自救了
and you still found a way to convince him to save himself.
"你内心知道
"There's a part of you that knows
不必让自己的过去来定义你"
you don't have to let your past define you."
但史纳特在那时候已经与我们合作过了
Except Snart had already worked with us at that point.
冰霜杀手  你挑衅让她杀了你
Killer Frost, you dared her to kill you.
"动手吧  做个名副其实的冰霜杀手"
"Come on, live up to your name, Killer Frost!"
-然后她做了什么  -诺拉
- And what did she do? - Nora.
阿姆内特  可塑炸弹
Amunet, Plastique,
这个名单可以一直列下去
the list goes on and on.
诺拉  所有的这些时期  都是不同的
Nora, all... all of these times are... are different.
蝉甚至不在乎这一切结束时
Cicada doesn't even care if he lives
自己还是否还活着
when this is over.
我应该说些什么他才会在乎
What am I supposed to say that he'll care about?
你会知道的
You'll know.
闪电侠总会知道
The Flash always knows.
翻译进程 分析中...
你仔细想想看  反抑制序列
So, when you think about it, an anti-dampening array
是阻止蝉行动的一个办法
is the way to stop him in his tracks.
歇洛克  你很快可以回家了  高兴吗
Sherloque, are you happy to be going home soon?
我回去当然高兴
Of course I'm happy to go back.
我只是感觉
I just feel that...
这里还有更多工作没有完成
somehow there's more work to be done here.
我觉得他在说他的女朋友们
I think he's, uh, talking about his lady friend.
你要知道  我对于异地恋
You know, I have a bit of experience with these, uh,
有一点点经验
long-distance relationships.
对此我只有一个建议  分手魔方
I got one word for you. Holo-cube.
这东西非常管用
These things work wonders.
我请求你尽可能永远都不要说话
And I request that you stop speaking possibly forever.
我从你刚进来的谈话中推论出
I can deduce from your conversation when you came in
你的确追踪到蝉的下一个目标
that you have indeed tracked down Cicada's next target
但在促成蝉和闪电侠的对话上
but do need help facilitating the conversation
还需要帮助
between Cicada and The Flash.
对吗  是吧  很好
Correct? Yes? Oh, good.
跟我来  我给你解决方案
Come with me and I will give you the solution.
你什么时候弄明白的
When did you figure it out?
我会非常想念你们俩的
I will miss you both very much.
但你们会更加想念我的  来吧
But you will miss me more! Allez!
菲利普·马斯特
Philip Master!
一切还好吗
We good?
是的  菲利普·马斯特关在管道监狱里
Yes, Philip Master is secure in the pipeline.
制酸大师的真名是菲利普·马斯特
Wait, Acid Master's real name is Philip Master?
就是这个场景  和照片里一模一样
This is it. Just like in the photo.
闪电侠和蝉的最后的对峙
The last confrontation between Flash and Cicada.
怎么了
Oh, what's the matter?
你没有这个吗
You don't have one of these?
告辞
Bye-bye.
蝉
Cicada!
他还有多长时间
How long does he have?
那把匕首还能保持六十秒  可能更短
He has to hold that dagger for 60 seconds, maybe less.
闪电侠最好快点想出要说什么
Flash better figure out what he's going to say fast.
他会的  我知道他会的
He will. I know he will.
我不想打架
I don't want to fight.
我们有一种解药
We have a cure.
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
我们有办法治愈超能力者
We have a way to cure meta-humans.
我们有办法去除他们的超能力
We have a way to take their powers away.
我们希望你可以服用这个解药
We want you to take it.
我为什么要同意这样做
And why would I agree to do that?
你的名声
Your legacy.
我知道这一切会如何结束
I know how this ends.
你不停地杀戮
You keep killing,
你将作为一个怪物被铭记  而不是英雄
and you're remembered as a monster, not a hero.
但我们可以一起改变它
But we can change that together,
你可以拥有不同的传承
you can have a different legacy.
你只需要选择它
You just have to choose it.
我一点都不在乎我的名声
I don't give a damn about my legacy.
仅此而已  那是我们最后的机会
That was it. That was our last chance.
我们进行了全市的面部识别扫描
We ran citywide facial recognition scans
也扫描了蝉的匕首上的
and scanned for dark matter signals
暗物质信号
from Cicada's dagger.
那是我们最后和蝉对峙的机会
That was our last shot at confronting Cicada.
我们还不确定
We don't know that.
我们在改变时间线
We're changing the timeline.
诺拉在闪电侠博物馆看到的照片
That photo that Nora saw at the Flash museum,
现在可能不一样了
it could be different now.
可能根本不存在
Maybe it doesn't even exist.
毕竟  时间线是有延展性的
After all... the timeline is malleable.
我只是搞不明白为什么计划没有成功
I just don't understand why our plan didn't work.
是的  你们所做的一切都是正确的
Yeah, you guys did everything right.
不成功的唯一原因
The only reason it didn't work
是因为我没有说服到他
is because I couldn't convince him.
爸  你是闪电侠
Dad, you're the Flash.
当闪电侠发自肺腑说实话的时候
When the Flash speaks honestly from his heart,
人们都会听进去
people listen.
不是所有人
Not all people.
我们继续搜寻吧
Let's keep searching.
我去中城警局查一下蝉的档案
I'm gonna check the Cicada files at CCPD.
看看有没有漏掉什么
See if I missed anything.
诺拉
Nora.
我们只  我们只是需要创造
We just... we just need to create
另一个机遇之窗  好吗
another window of opportunity, okay?
爸爸没能说服蝉接受解药
Dad couldn't convince Cicada to take the cure.
他只是  他只需要找到恰当的话语
He just... he just needs to find the right words.
巴仔
Bare.
这么晚你在这里干嘛
What are you doing here so late?
在尖端科研实验室追踪蝉碰壁了
We hit a wall at S.T.A.R. Labs tracking Cicada.
我以为换个环境会有助于思考  可是
Thought a change of scenery would help, but...
别气馁  老弟
Keep your head up, man.
我们会找到他的  我们总能做到
We'll find him. We always do.
说实话
Honestly,
我更担心的是找到他之后该怎么做
I'm more worried about what happens when we do.
整个计划的成败取决于我能否说服德怀尔
Our whole plan depends on me being able to convince Dwyer
接受解药
to just take the cure.
上次我尝试时
The last time I tried...
我没想到会那么失败
I don't think I've ever struck out so hard.
那真的挺差劲的
Wow, that's saying a lot
鉴于你在本垒的历史记录
considering your track record at the plate.
慢着  你到底跟他说了什么
Wait, what exactly did you say to him?
说他正在创造一个将载入史册的
That he was creating a legacy of fear,
令人恐惧的名声
one that would go down in history,
但我们可以共同合作改变它
but that we could work together to change that.
这听起来就像闪电侠说的话
That sounds like something the Flash would say.
我就是闪电侠
Well, I am the Flash.
听着  那个人是狂热者
Look, that man's a zealot.
他看着你这身战衣
He sees you in that suit
看见的都是他所憎恨的东西
and all he sees is the thing he hates.
超能力者  超能力
Meta-human, superpowers,
从他身边夺走侄女的那些东西
the thing that took his niece away from him.
他的视野无法越过闪电侠
He can't see past the Flash,
但他不知道的是
but what he doesn't know...
你远远不仅仅是闪电侠
There's a whole lot more to you than that.
更多的做巴里·艾伦  普通人
Be more Barry Allen. Human.
是的  你说得对
Yeah, you're right.
谢谢你  我打算继续工作
Thanks. I'm gonna dive back in.
我就不妨碍你追查安布勒斯了
I'll let you get back to running down Ambres.
实际上
Actually...
我和塞西尔遇到了阻碍
me and Cecile ran into a wall ourselves.
我们  她...  无法一起工作
We are... uh, she... like, working together.
自从她得到了超能力
I mean, ever since she got her powers,
她就像是个人形测谎仪
it's like she's a human lie detector.
这怎么是坏事呢
How is that a bad thing?
你知道我一直自豪于
You know I've always prided myself
能看透他人的想法  是吧
on being able to read people, right?
但塞西尔这超能力  她把我比下去了
But Cecile and these powers, I mean, she puts me to shame.
你只需要记住你们是一个团队
Well, you just got to remember that you guys are a team.
她的力量也是你的力量
That makes her strengths your strengths
反过来也一样
and yours hers.
所以如果你让她做擅长的事
So if you let her do what she's great at,
这只会为你创造更多的空间
it's only going to create more room
去做更多你也擅长的事情  对吧
for you to do more of what you're great at too, right?
好吧  该死
Well, damn.
你越来越会激励人了  巴仔
You're getting real good at these pep talks, Bare.
我可是有个很好的老师
Well, I had a pretty good teacher.
诺拉
Hey, Nora.
Hi, Nora.
听到了
Yeah.
你能把音量调低一点吗
Do you want to turn that down a little bit?
对不起
Oh, sorry.
你在听什么
What are you listening to?
加速后的闪电侠通信记录存档
Sped-up archives of the Flash's comm recordings.
我觉得如果我听了他的最佳演讲
I thought that if I listen to his best appeals,
我就能搞清楚到底是什么这么有用
I could figure out what exactly worked so well.
你搞定了吗
And did you?
不  还没有
No, not yet.
但如果我在电脑上运行这些文字
But if I run the transcripts through the computer,
我可以从他最成功的演讲中
I can extrapolate recurring key words
推断出重复出现的关键词
from his most successful appeals
然后创造出一种"最佳演讲合集"的演讲
and create a sort of "Best of Speeches" Speech.
好吧
Well, um,
你不如让你爸爸来思考这个
why don't you let your dad think about it
我们可以去吉特咖啡的屋顶
and we could go to the rooftop of Jitters.
那是个让你头脑清醒的好地方
It's a great place to clear your mind,
还能欣赏到市里最好的景色
plus it's got the best views of the city.
你想去观光吗  现在
You want to go sightseeing? Right now?
这是你那个清单里的一条吗
What... is this from that list of yours?
是的  但是...
Well, yeah, but...
一整天我都在想办法阻止蝉
All day I've been trying to figure out a way to stop Cicada
可一整天你都想把我拉走
and all day you've been trying to pull me away.
你为什么要推进这个清单
Why are you pushing this list?
这可能是我们
I mean, it's just the last time
最后一次聚在一起
that we may get to spend together.
诺拉  一旦我们阻止了蝉
Nora, I mean, once we stop Cicada,
你就会回到你的时间去...
you'll go back to your time and...
我们像这样在一起的日子就结束了
Us like this together will end.
妈妈  这不会结束
Mom, it doesn't end.
我们的整个未来都在一起
We have our whole future together.
是的  对你来说  感觉就像时间没有流逝
Yeah, for you it'll feel like no time has passed
但对我而言  下次像这样见到你之前...
but for me, it'll be decades before I...
就像过了几十年
see you like this again.
不  没事的
Uh, no, it's okay.
等会再跟你聊
Um, I will catch up with you later.
乔
Joe.
怎么了
What's going on?
为什么你想在这里见面
Why'd you want me to meet you here?
听着  上次我们试着一起工作的时候
Look, I know the last time we tried to work together
有点失败
went a bit south.
只是有点吗
Oh, a bit?
你是对的  我很抱歉  塞西尔
You're right. I'm sorry, Cecile.
我的骄傲碍事了
I let my pride get in the way,
应该依靠你的力量的时候
and I didn't lean on your strengths
我却没有那么做
when I should have.
但你懂我的
But you know me,
我不是个会犯两次相同错误的人
I'm not a man who makes the same mistake twice.
所以...
So...
你能赏光
Would you do me the honor
和我一起来审讯吗
of joining me in this interrogation?
你做你最擅长的事  我会搞定剩下的
You do what you do best, I'll take care of the rest.
去吧  姑娘
Get 'em, girl.
警探  地方检察官
Detective. DA.
这近乎于骚扰了
This is starting to border on harassment.
我把我知道的一切都告诉你们了
I have told you everything I know.
不是那样的
That's not true.
我们知道你一直在给奥林·德怀尔提供药
We know that you've been funneling meds to Orlin Dwyer.
如果你们知道了的话
Well, if you knew that,
我会被逮捕而不是坐在这里
then I'd be arrested and not sitting here.
我纠正一下说法
Let me correct myself.
我们有强烈的预感
We have a strong hunch,
但我敢打赌如果我们
but I bet if we were to go through
彻查医院的摄像机镜头
the video camera footage from the hospital,
我们会找到你协助德怀尔的证据
we'll find proof that you were assisting Dwyer.
我是个医生
I'm a doctor.
我为什么要纵容一个义警杀人犯呢
I mean, why would I condone a vigilante murderer?
因为发生在达留斯身上的事
Because of what happened to Darius.
达留斯
Darius.
想想都会让你受伤
It hurts you to even think about it.
我的未婚夫在极速为非作歹的时候
My fiancé  was killed by meta-humans
被超能力者杀死了
during Zoom's rampage.
所以是的  想到他很痛苦
So, yes, it hurts to think about him.
痛到足以让你帮助德怀尔杀死其他超能力者吗
Hurt enough for you to help Dwyer kill other meta-humans?
如果我没记错的话
Correct me if I'm wrong,
你发过誓不伤害别人  对吧
you took an oath to do no harm, right?
你能如实地说你遵守了那个誓言吗
Can you truthfully say you've upheld that oath?
你现在感觉到的内疚
That guilt that you feel right now?
有个办法可以弥补
There's a way to make up for it.
你要做的就是帮我们找到奥林
All you have to do is help us find Orlin.
这样你们好把他关进监狱吗  还是杀了他
What, so... so you can put him in jail? Kill him?
不  我们会治好他
No, so we can cure him.
不可能
It's not possible.
也许不是靠你一直在给他的药
Maybe not with the medicine you've been giving him,
而是尖端科研实验室创造了一种解药
but S.T.A.R. Labs has created a treatment
能把超能力者变成正常人
that turns metas back into normal human beings.
我不能带你去见他
I can't take you to him.
好的  没事  那帮我们安排个会面
Okay, okay, then help us set up a meet.
听着  安布勒斯医生  很清楚了
Look, Dr. Ambres, it's clear.
你真的很关心德怀尔
You've come to truly care for Dwyer.
所以我们现在请求你...
So we're asking you now...
帮我们救他的命
help us save his life.
我可以去联系  也可以告诉你们位置
I can make contact, and I can share the location.
我一个小时内要轮班
I have rounds in an hour
还有今晚我可以拯救的病人
and patients that I can save tonight.
拜托了  我能走了吗
So am I free to go, please?
我热爱我的工作
I love my job.
我可以在这里待一整晚
I can stay here all night.
我们都会  除非你告诉我们
And we will, unless you tell us
你现在还在隐藏些什么
what you're keeping hidden right now.
我收到你的短信了  你跟安布勒斯谈过了
Yo, yo. I got your text. You talked to Ambres?
我和塞西尔一起说服了她
Cecile and I together got through to her.
她会告诉我们如何找到德怀尔
She's going to show us where to find Dwyer.
乔  这太棒了
Joe, that's amazing.
是的  安布勒斯还告诉我们些别的事情
Yeah, Ambres told us something else.
德怀尔的侄女  格蕾丝  她是个超能力者
Dwyer's niece, Grace? She's a meta.
[法语]
原来"小德怀尔"是个超能力者
So le petit Dwyer is a meta.
等等  我以为诺拉进入她的大脑时
Wait, I thought we scanned Grace for meta powers
我们已经对格蕾丝进行过超能力扫描
when Nora entered her brain.
确实  但那时她的DNA还完全是人类
We did but that was back when her DNA was 100% human.
她的超能力肯定是在过去
Her powers must have activated
短短几个礼拜被激活的  对吗
in just the last few weeks, right?
对  安布勒斯告诉乔  格蕾丝头上的伤口
Yeah, Ambres told Joe that the wound in Grace's head
最近开始发光和变异
recently started glowing and mutating.
现在我们需要再让德怀尔和你聊聊
Now all we need to do is get Dwyer to listen to you, again.
冰霜杀手可以把他从脖子以下冻住
Killer Frost can put him on ice from the neck down.
更好的是  我可以重新排序神速力火箭炮
Better yet, I can re-sequence the Speed Force Bazooka
-使他的负快子超负荷  -没错
- to overload him with negative tachyons. - Yes.
-绝对可以  -那样他就动不了了
- Absolutely. - So that he's stuck there...
什么快子  你个蠢蛋  那不行
Tachyon, shmack-yon. No, no.
我们应该用记忆机
La Machine  à  Mémoire!
我们可以进入德怀尔的脑子
We could go inside Dwyer's mind.
-这个嘛... -伙计们
- Oh, about that... - Guys...
-用记忆机更好  -上次  我想...
- No, La Machine  à  Mémoire! - Last time? I think...
伙计们  别吵了
Guys, hey!
我很感激你们积极出谋划策
I appreciate the enthusiasm,
不过我想我们需要用其他的方式
but I think we need to take a different approach.
不要超能力  不要疯狂的计划
No powers, no crazy plans.
闪电侠无法说服蝉停手
The Flash can't convince Cicada to stop this,
但是  也许
but... maybe...
我可以
I can.
爸爸回来了
Dad's back.
他说乔爷爷有关于德怀尔的消息
He says Papa Joe's got news about Dwyer.
好的  那我们去表层控制室吧
Okay, good. I guess we should get over to the Cortex.
你知道吗  我也有个清单
You know, I had a list too.
你的婚礼  詹娜阿姨的宝宝洗礼
Your wedding, Auntie Jenna's baby shower,
吉特  大悟之道
Jitters, The Enlightenment.
这些都是你想要时间旅行回去
Those were all the moments in time
拜访我们的时刻吗
you wanted to go back and see us?
对  这样我就可以和你们所有人
Yeah, so I could have memories and experiences
都有同样的记忆和经历
with all of you.
我懂的
I get it.
我应该更体谅你  对不起
I should've been sensitive and I-I'm so sorry.
-没关系  -有关系的
- It's okay. - No, it's not.
我太专注于想办法帮助闪电侠打败蝉
I was so focused on making sure Flash beat Cicada,
忘记了我真正应该关注的事情
I forgot what I was supposed to really be focused on.
你和爸爸
You and Dad.
你们才是我回到现在的原因
You're the reason I came back to this time,
而不是与坏人斗争或者得到以我命名的咖啡
not fighting big bads or getting my own XS-presso.
我只是想和我的父母共度时光
So that I could spend time with my parents.
和我的家庭相处
My family.
我不知道我们还剩多少时间可以共度
I don't know how much time we have left together
或者你列在清单上的事我们还能完成多少
or how much of your list we're going to get done,
但从现在开始  剩下的每一刻
but from now on, every moment we have left,
我们都会让它值得纪念
we're going to make it a memorable one.
我保证
I promise.
我想"一边喝茶一边拥抱"这一项
Well, I guess we can cross off "Hugging while drinking tea"
-可以从清单上划掉了  -是啊
- off our list. - Yeah.
伙计们  抱歉打断一下
Hey, guys, sorry to interrupt.
-没关系  -我们只是
- No, it's fine. - We were just...
只是在谈论妈妈的清单
We were just talking about Mom's list.
我听说我爸有德怀尔的新线索
Um, so I heard Dad has a lead on Dwyer?
我们有他的方位了
We have a location.
我很快会去找他
I'm going to head there any minute.
闪电侠准备好这次如何说服他了吗
Does Flash know what he's going to say this time?
实际上  我只想和他聊聊
Actually, I think I'm just gonna talk to him,
以一个父亲对父亲的方式
father to father.
这个主意太棒了  爸爸
That's a really good idea, Dad.
医生  你好
Hey, Doc.
安布勒斯医生告诉我们在这里找你
Dr. Ambres told us where to find you.
我只想和你聊聊
I just want to talk.
我们没什么好聊的
There's no more talking.
每次你们超能力者接近我们
Every time one of you metas comes near the rest of us,
好人就会受到伤害
good people get hurt.
这是你们应得的
This is what you all deserve.
这也是格蕾丝应得的吗
Does that include Grace?
安布勒斯还没告诉你
Ambres hasn't told you.
格蕾丝  她也是超能力者了
Grace. She's a meta.
卫星坠毁的那一晚
The night the satellite crashed,
她被一片带有暗物质的碎片砸中
she was hit with a piece of shrapnel inflected with dark matter.
她因此陷入昏迷
That's... that's why she's in a coma,
现在暗物质正在改变她
and now it's changing her.
你在骗我
That's a lie.
因此安布勒斯才告诉我们来这里找你
And that's why Ambres told us where to find you.
她害怕了
She's afraid.
她害怕你会做出令自己抱憾终生的事情
She's afraid you're going to do the one thing you can't come back from.
我知道你非常在意格蕾丝
I know how much you care about Grace.
你在努力为她让这个世界变得更好
You're trying to make the world a better place for her.
她并没有选择成为一个超能力者
She didn't choose to be a meta,
但她现在确实是
but she is.
难道她也该死吗
Does that mean she deserves to die?
不
No.
我永远不会伤害格蕾丝
I would never hurt Grace.
你会让她生活在一个充满恐惧的世界里吗
Then you'd let her grow up in a world of fear.
一个有人会伤害像她一样的人的世界里
Where there's someone out there hurting people like her.
解药  能够治愈格蕾丝  还有你
The cure, it will heal Grace and you.
我为什么要相信你  闪电侠
And why should I believe you, Flash?
因为我也是一名父亲
Because I'm a father too.
我的女儿  我爱她胜过一切
My daughter, I love her more than I ever thought possible.
为了让她生活在一个更美好的世界
I would do anything to make the world
我会做任何事情
a better place for her.
我认为你也会这么做
And I think you would too.
接受解药吧
So do it.
我们商量好了
We made an arrangement.
我们先治愈他  然后治愈格蕾丝
We cure him and then Grace.
好
Okay.
我们为什么在这里而不去医院
Why are we here and not at a hospital?
我们必须确保解药成功
We have to be sure that the cure is successful.
我们发明的
We created it.
我们才是知道它如何运作的人
We're the ones who know how it works.
一旦使用  解药将在60秒内
Once administered, the cure will take 60 seconds
消除你系统内的超能力
to eliminate the meta-human powers in your system.
那意味着你胸腔中的伤口会打开
That means the wound in your chest will then open.
你需要我将其缝合
You'll need me to suture it shut
否则你会血流不止
so you don't bleed out.
为什么不是安布勒斯医生
Why not Doc Ambres?
她正在接受审问
She's being held for questioning.
不  必须是安布勒斯  否则就算了
No, it's Ambres, or we're done.
好吧  我们去找她
All right, we'll get her.
如果出现任何差错
If anything goes wrong,
或者你们对我撒谎
or if you're lying to me,
我会杀了你们
I'll kill every...
每个人
last...one of you.
确定这个房间中所有的都是无菌的吗
And we're certain everything in this room is sterile?
当然
Of course.
除了那个
Everything except that.
那不能动
That thing's not negotiable.
他的愤怒  太...
That rage of his, it's...
乔  我不能
Joe, I can't.
你会留下吗
Are you going to stay?
是的  以防万一
Uh, yeah, just in case.
-好的  -好的  亲爱的
- Okay. - All right, babe.
今天干得不错
Good job today.
你也是  搭档
You too. Partner.
没有你们我们做不到
We never could have done this without you guys.
能成功我很高兴
Well, I'm glad it worked out,
但这结束后  他得进监狱
but when this is over, he's going to jail,
关上好久
for a long time.
好的  一份新鲜出炉的超能力解药
Okay, one fresh serving of piping hot meta-human cure.
我应该相信那东西有用吗
I'm just supposed to trust that that thing works?
它有经过人体试验吗
Has it gone through any human testing?
经过大型鲨鱼试验
It's gone through giant shark testing.
说来话长
It's a long story.
没事的  医生
It's okay, Doc.
我想告诉你有关格蕾丝的真相
I wanted to tell you the truth about Grace.
我只是找不到合适的词
I just couldn't find the words.
你只是想保证她的安全
You were just trying to keep her safe.
我会永远感激你的
I'll always be thankful for that.
那边见
See you on the other side.
开始了
There we go.
注射解药
Injecting the cure.
他的生命指数在激增
His vitals are spiking.
我们怎么知道解药起作用了
How can we tell if the cure is even working?
起作用了
Oh, it's working.
我的超能力回来了
My powers are back.
那就意味着德怀尔的消失了
Which means Dwyer's powers must be gone.
看来你在过去的逗留是成功的
It appears your sojourn into the past was a success.
恭喜
Congratulations.
谢谢
Thank you.
你也是  是你的第三十八个蝉吗
You as well. It's your, uh, 38th Cicada?
没错
That's right, yes.
三十八号蝉  第三十八个蝉
38th Cicada. Trente-huit Cicada.
大满贯
Alley-oop!
当然  这里还有些事情
But, of course, there's some business here
尚未完成
that remains unfinished.
比如说  在你看到图片里的烧痕之前
For instance, how did you know before you saw the burn marks
你怎么知道会是超能力者
in the photograph that it was a meta-human
带我们找到蝉
that would lead us to Cicada?
我
Uh, I...
我就是有种感觉
You know, I just had this feeling
大事即将发生
that something big was coming.
他们现在正在治疗他
They're working on him now.
这些都结束时我会好开心
I will be so happy when this is all over with.
怎么了
What's going on?
怎么停电了
What happened to the power?
我不知道
I have no idea.
我得检查下医务室
I should check the Med Lab.
-有人来了  -谁
- Someone's coming. - Who?
蝉吗
Cicada?
这是怎么回事
Where's that coming from?
西斯科
Cisco!
-等下  -爱瑞丝
- Hold on! - Iris.
-小心  -我什么也看不到
- Careful. - I can't see anything.
这里
Here.
西斯科  我们需要电
Cisco, we need power.
我们有个更严重的问题
We got a much bigger problem.
蝉
Cicada?
那到底怎么发生的
How the hell did that happen?
我不知道  但他来了而且很愤怒
I don't know, but he's coming here and he looks pissed.
我们现在得走了
We have to move now.
我得接着把他缝好
I've got to keep patching him up.
往后站
Stand back.
好了
There.
-他在走廊  -快离开这里
- He's in the hallway. - Get the hell out of here.
爱瑞丝  趴下
Iris! Get down!
快啊
Come on!
你是谁
Who are you?
不管你是谁
Please, whoever you are.
我只是为了让他变回正常人
I only came here to make him human again!
我帮了他
I helped him!
拜托
Please!
拜托别这样
Please don't do this!
不行  全都坏掉了
Nope. They're all toast.
电脑遭殃总好过是我们
Well, better the computers than us.
-乔  -你还好吗
- Joe. - Are you okay?
-我还好  -我有点青肿  但...
- I'm okay, I'm okay. - I'm a little bruised, but...
其他人呢
Everybody else?
我们都还好
Yeah, we're okay.
-各位  -安布勒斯医生没能撑过去
- Guys... - Dr. Ambres didn't make it.
到处都没有他们的踪迹
There's no sign of them anywhere.
我不明白发生了什么
I don't understand what happened.
我们找到了德怀尔  给他了解药
I mean, we got Dwyer, we gave him the cure.
如果蝉不存在了  那又是谁
If... if Cicada doesn't exist anymore, who was that?
更可怕的人
Someone worse.
我好想你
I've missed you.
奥林叔叔
Uncle Orlin.